Think back to when he was still a cop.
Sergeant Padej wasn't exactly
a good cop either.
All right, that's enough!
He was framed in that case.
Don't tell me you and Luang Pho
knew each other before all this?
Someone told me that.
Who? Who told you?
I can't tell you.
Even if money were piled high
as a mountain,
you would never sell out
your integrity as an officer?
How could you betray
your own ideals like this?
PREVIOUSLY
So what's your next move?
I have to return to Bangkok.
There's no way I'm letting Papon
get away with my diamond.
Go back and stay with Luang Pho Suea.
Try to find out
if the diamond is really with him,
and if so,
find out where he hid it.
He has refused to help me before.
Then how are you going
to get him to help us?
Why did you want to see me?
I want to know what you think
of Captain Chansuek's case.
-Why do you ask?
-Just answer me.
Do you think Captain Chansuek
really stole the diamond?
That kind of question
in this kind of place…
Just like back then, right?
Kan.
6 YEARS AGO
Do you really believe Padej
stole that diamond?
You don't believe it.
You know Sergeant Padej is a good man.
I think he was definitely framed.
It's not my division's case.
I don't know the details.
The detectives say
the evidence against him
is pretty solid, Ya.
But I don't believe he'd do such a thing.
He saved my life.
I owe him, Kan.
Ya.
Sometimes, too much faith…
makes you blind to the fact that
a good man can make mistakes.
Someone who saved you can make mistakes.
Are you saying I misjudged him, Kan?
I'm not.
Don't mix his past good deeds
with the facts of this case.
Otherwise, your reporting will be led
by your heart, not your head.
Isn't that a bit harsh?
Sorry.
I just wanted to remind you.
You don't need to.
I know how to separate
my personal feelings from my job.
More importantly,
even if I write stories
with my heart, not my head,
I won't be as cruel as cops
who only use their heads,
but never have a heart, like you people.
After that, our disagreement
got worse and worse,
all because of Sergeant Padej's case.
Eventually, we broke up.
You broke up with me.
I didn't want to break up.
Enough. Let's stop talking about the past.
Agreed.
I didn't think we would be having
the same conversation again.
So what do you think?
What I think doesn't matter.
After all,
you chose to believe
and help Captain Chansuek anyway.
You know?
I've always known.
I just don't have proof
and haven't seen it with my own eyes.
Okay. I admit.
Will you arrest me?
Are you that into him?
Have you lost your mind?
I'm not into him.
So why would you help him?
I want to find out the truth.
That's why your opinion matters in this.
I need your help.
My opinion is unchanged, Ya.
Evidence will decide.
I shouldn't have come.
Go find some proof.
Find what made you curious
and eager to find the truth.
Then I'll help you.
How does Chansuek feel about this?
Well…
Just tell me.
Paul can hear it.
Can you?
Do you care about Chansuek that much?
Do you love him
and want to help him so badly?
Let me go!
What are you doing?
Just doing what couples do.
Not here. Someone might see us.
Jealous?
Boss.
I didn't think you were really into her.
Not that much, boss.
After all, work is more important.
Good.
I'm glad you realize that.
Remember.
Women are nothing.
One day, when you have wealth,
fame, and titles,
better women,
better-looking women…
will line up for you to choose.
Right.
This story is interesting, Noona.
Yes. We need to get to the bottom of it.
CHATCHAWAN
PRIVATE DETECTIVE AGENCY
The diamond was stolen
on its way to the bank's vault.
The bank staff and the insurance staff
on security duty were all killed.
So who knew that Ms. Yok
would be transporting
the diamond that day?
The bank employees,
the insurance employees,
and…
-Ms. Yok!
Right, Dad?
I think it must be just as I thought.
Ms. Yok staged the heist herself?
Dad, think about it.
Who benefits the most
if the diamond is lost?
Ms. Yok.
That's right.
Then we start with Ms. Yok.
Right. Okay.
That's settled. Meeting's over.
Where are you going?
To see Captain Chansuek?
I have to bring him something.
I have to go.
Wait.
Gosh. What now, Dad?
Be careful what you do.
Don't let him know you're a detective
working on his case.
You could get in trouble.
Hey, Dad.
You can trust me. He won't know.
Bye.
You're too bossy.
Because it feels like
you're trying to find excuses
to clear him of suspicion.
Why on earth would you think that?
Luang Pho always helped you.
And you believed that person
over the monk who saved your life?
What's wrong with him?
Ever since he went
with that bubblegum lady,
he's been acting like this.
Hey!
You're a kid.
How can you say that about an adult?
So who's that bubblegum lady
that you mentioned?
I thought you knew.
And yet you told me off?
The lady who said
she was junior disciple's girlfriend.
Well…
Good morning, Luang Pho.
Morning.
Are you here to see Boonrod?
Yeah.
Why is he zoning out over there?
I don't know either.
Okay. I'll just go and talk to him.
Let's go.
Here.
For me?
Yeah, so we can keep in touch.
It's necessary to have a phone these days.
Save my number, and we can get in touch.
Thanks.
What's wrong with you?
I don't know.
I'm so confused.
Confused?
About what?
Well…
Everything.
It makes no sense.
I don't know how it will end.
But that's no surprise.
This is me.
I don't even know myself well enough.
I see.
Let's go.
Go where?
Just come with me.
-Hey…
-Get up.
Where?
Hey, wait.
What are you doing?
I'm going inside.
You can't.
Entering someone's home
without permission is trespassing.
You're being a full-on cop now?
That's the law.
You could even be charged
with property damage and theft.
Whose place is this?
Captain Chansuek's.
Is this my house?
Yeah.
So what? Are you still arresting me now?
Who would arrest you?
You're a pro.
Have you ever committed burglary?
Are you coming in?
Whose place is this?
Is this my house?
Yeah.
Didn't you want to learn more
about yourself?
This is the best way.
PRESENTED TO CHANSUEK
FOR EXEMPLARY PUBLIC SERVICE
You're right.
Being back at my own place
helped me remember who I truly am.
You seem to be a good man.
You've won a lot of awards.
These things don't tell you
whether someone is good or not.
At least I see your hard work.
Are these…
all yours?
Gosh.
I wanted this one,
but couldn't find it anywhere.
Do you collect action figures?
I can't believe it.
What kind of woman collects them?
Well…
A woman like me.
Why would I have become a…
What?
Why would I have become a photographer?
Photographer?
How's that related?
Yeah. It is.
Didn't you and everyone else
tell me not to come home?
I was afraid you'd be in danger.
I was afraid the people
coming after you would find you.
Is it safe now, then?
Just take a quick look and leave.
Why would you stay for long?
It feels quiet.
Did I live alone?
Wait…
I have parents.
Who in the world doesn't have parents?
You think you were born from a bamboo?
Hey.
I didn't mean it that way.
I mean if I have parents,
where are they now?
Well…
From what I was told,
they both passed away in an accident.
Then…
That means I'm alone in this world.
Idiot. You're not alone.
You still have your grandma.
She raised you.
And you love her so much.
You have to visit her more often.
Grandma?
Grandma…
Grandma!
What's wrong?
My head hurts.
Sit down.
Sit here and rest.
How are you feeling?
I'm fine now.
All of a sudden,
I saw a flashback of Grandma.
So that means coming here…
helped you remember something.
Familiar places and surroundings
seem to help.
Deputy Papon.
Deputy Papon was your boss.
I think you know that.
You seem to admire Deputy Papon.
Weird. I don't see it.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
What are you looking for?
Nothing.
I think we should go.
Wait! Hold on!
What the heck are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I didn't know what you were looking for.
Why didn't you tell me?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I was…
I was just wondering why you don't have
a photo with your girlfriend.
Da.
Yeah.
You're right.
I think you learned enough about yourself.
We should go.
Hey, wait.
I wonder how my grandma is doing.
She's doing fine.
She's worried.
How did you know?
Well…
I saw her before the trip to Mae Hong Son.
Wait. Why did you see my grandma?
Why?
Well…
I just ran into her.
That doesn't sound right.
You know where I live.
You know my history.
And you ran into my grandma.
It feels like you were investigating me.
Are you crazy?
I saw your grandma by chance.
Your address and background.
I found out about it in Bangkok.
I should not have helped you.
Hey, wait.
Noona, wait.
Wait a minute!
Hey.
Wait for me.
Wait, Noona.
Wait. Are you mad at me?
I'm not mad.
I'm just annoyed.
If you don't trust me
or if you suspect me…
-I want nothing to do with you.
-No. I just… Okay, I'm sorry.
I won't suspect you anymore.
That's good.
We should go.
Hey. Duck.
Let's go.
-Let's go!
-Hey!
I think we lost him.
Kamnan Sawaeng's man followed us here?
So he knew we fled to Bangkok.
That was quick.
Right.
We have to be more careful.
Yeah.
Let's head home.
Where's your home? I'll walk you there.
Gosh, there's no need.
Why not?
You said we need to be careful.
You be careful.
You too, Noona.
Don't forget we're in the same boat now.
I care about you.
I don't want them to hurt you.
Well, don't worry about me.
I'm not going home.
And they're not after me
like they're after you.
Besides, nobody knows me.
All of them are after you.
Wait.
If you aren't going home,
where are you going?
I…
I'm staying at my friend's.
I can't really be seen with you.
Oh, I see.
I should get going.
My friend's place is the other way.
Okay.
This woman is Noona.
She's a former cop.
She left the force
and became a private detective.
Is this who you really are?
CHATCHAWAN
PRIVATE DETECTIVE AGENCY
I've arrived at my friend's. Don't worry.
What about you? Did you get there safely?
You should get some rest.
Goodbye, then.
Don't forget we're in the same boat now.
I care about you.
I don't want them to hurt you.
I'm sorry.
I had to lie.
You're right.
Being back at my own place
helped me remember who I truly am.
-Hey!
-Let's go! Move!
Goodness!
You always sneak up on me.
Haven't you gotten used to it yet?
Hey.
Boonrod, you're here?
Yes.
Luang Pho, he has a phone.
Well, Noona gave it to me.
That's good.
Now you're easy to reach.
So where have you been today?
Noona took me to my home today
to help me remember myself as Chansuek.
So what do you remember?
Boonrod, hey.
-Boonrod.
-My head hurts.
-What's wrong? Boonrod!
-Junior.
Junior!
Boonrod! Are you okay?
-What's wrong?
-Junior!
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Do you need some pills?
What's wrong?
I'm fine.
-I'll sleep it off.
-What?
What's wrong with you?
Well, you should get some rest.
Tofu, come on. Leave him alone.
Get some sleep.
Here.
"Truly living life in a…
monk's robe."
CHATCHAWAN
PRIVATE DETECTIVE AGENCY
Noona? She's sleeping.
Noona.
Noona, wake up.
Wake up.
Dad.
Why wake me up? I need to sleep.
Go sleep upstairs.
I have a client meeting.
What?
If you sleep here and the client sees you,
it will look bad for our agency.
Everybody sleeps.
Go sleep upstairs. Take your stuff.
Give me a sec.
-Go.
-Isn't it too early?
Just go already.
-I'm going.
-Go.
Gosh.
Da.
What is this place?
A private detective agency.
So why did you take me here?
I want a detective to investigate my dad.
I suspect he was set up
to be indebted to Paul.
Please come in with me.
You can help me talk to them.
Okay.
-Good morning.
We have a meeting.
I'll get some water. Sit down.
Please take a seat.
Here's your drink.
You…
Noona.
What are you doing here?
"Areena Patimakorn."
"Private Detective."
Here it is, Chan.
Your answer.
You're a detective?
Yes.
So that means…
You approached Chan
as part of what investigation exactly?
Well…
You're investigating me?
Yes.
Boonrod.
Stop. Hey, you.
Would it kill you to listen to me?
Just say what you want.
Yes.
I lied.
I went into the forest
to search for the lost diamond.
But I never meant to come after you.
Everything that happened in the forest
was an accident.
It was just a coincidence.
Well, are you playing
the "fate" card, detective?
Chan doesn't believe you.
Do you, Chan?
But I'm telling the truth.
Only a fool would believe you.
How could everything
play out exactly like that
if you never meant to go after Chan?
Boonrod.
You have to believe me.
Let's go, Da.
You've been lying this whole time?
All this time,
what part was real?
I'm okay, Dad. Why wouldn't I be?
It's a good thing.
I don't have to hide anything now.
-You're here for me?
-That's right. We have to go.
Go where?
Come with me. You'll find out.
Wait, Luang Pho. Stop.
NEXT EPISODE
Why?
Are you better than me? You liar.
If one day,
you found someone
who hurt you in the past,
someone who completely ruined your life,
would you be able to forgive them?
This woman just feels bad
because she got caught.
She doesn't regret it.
Sometimes, doing your job
can break your heart, you know.
Subtitle translation by: Aoy M.